https://www.ucc.ie/privacy

Study
CoursesUndergraduatePostgraduateInternational OfficeAdult Continuing EducationUCC OnlineContinuing Professional DevelopmentScholarships and PrizesTransition-In ProgrammeGraduate AttributesAskIncoming First Year StudentsApply to UCCCollaborative Programmes
Research & Innovation
About UCC ResearchResearch Institutes and CentresResearch Support ServicesResearch ExpertiseInnovation and Technology TransferResearch View Newsletter
Discover UCC
HistoryNews and ViewsLeadership and StrategyCampus LifeVisit UCCAwardsCork City and RegionTogether with Community
Schools & Departments
Academic Schools and DepartmentsSupport and Service Departments
Business & Enterprise
Work with UCC StudentsRecruit UCC GraduatesExecutive EducationCentre for Continuing Professional DevelopmentResearch and InnovationEntrepreneurship Resources
Alumni & Development
Meet PeopleMake an ImpactDiscover our AlumniExplore BenefitsRegister for UCC Alumni OnlineMake a Gift
Home
Visited Pages
Favourites
Close
Search UCC.ie
Site Search Text
Website
People
Guidance on Level 3 Restrictions
We've updated our guidance based on the move to Level 3 restrictions in Dec 2020. Find out what this means for your studies, research and work.
Updated 2 Dec 2020
In This Section
HomeAcademic Policy PortalComplianceCur chun cinn na Gaeilge i Saol na hOllscoile
Foreword
Statute K
Policy document in relation to the advancement of Irish
Examinations Finance Office - Policies
Accounts Payable
Banking/Cash
Fixed Asset
Other Policies
Email
HomeSupportPolicies and ProceduresIT PoliciesPoliciesPrivacy
Privacy
Privacy Statement
This statement relates to the privacy practices of University College Cork – National University of Ireland, Cork (“the University”) in connection with the University’s main web pages (i.e. those in www.ucc.ie).Other sites run by the University may carry their own privacy policy and/or provide additional information relating to their activities, which will supersede or supplement this privacy statement.
General statement
The University fully respects your right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share personal information (also known as personal data) with the University.
How we use your personal data and our legal basis for this
On some parts of the website, you may volunteer personal information (for example by using our online forms, applying for a vacancy, registering to use certain website platforms etc.). The University principally uses your information under the legal basis of consent. An example of this would be a request to be added to a mailing list (which will be used to send you newsletters and information). As this information is provided on the basis of consent, you are free to withdraw your consent at any time. The University may also process your information under the legal basis of contract whereby the processing is necessary for a contract you have with us, or because you have asked us to take specific steps before entering into a contract).
We also collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our webmasters. This allows us to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. The use of your personal information in the above ways is necessary for the legitimate interests of the University in operating and improving its websites, analysing their use, and ensuring their security. For more information please review our cookie policy.
Any personal information processed by the University in connection with these websites will be treated in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and the Data Protection Acts 1988 to 2018. Accordingly, the University shall only process such information in line with the purpose for which you provided it to the extent necessary to provide you with the information or service you require.
The University shall not disclose your information to third parties unless you are specifically informed otherwise or we require a third party contractors to process the information on our behalf (in which case the University requires these third parties to comply with its instructions and we require that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way).
How long we will keep your data
In keeping with the data protection principles, we will only store your data for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was submitted to the University and in accordance with the University’s Records Management Policy and records retention schedules.
Cross-border data transfers
We work with third party contractors, some of whom operate and host data outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Accordingly, in the course of processing your personal data, it may be transferred outside of the EEA on the understanding that we rely on legally approved mechanisms to lawfully transfer data across borders including the Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission.
Links
The University is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. The privacy practices on these websites may differ from that on the University’s websites, and we advise that you review the other websites’ policies before providing personal information.
Within the University domain (.ucc.ie) you may find websites over which the University has no editorial responsibility. Such sites can include the websites of student organisations, etc. While the University expects compliance with this privacy statement at such sites, please contact the Digital Estate Working Group if you encounter University websites that are not compliant with this privacy statement.
Your Rights
You have various rights under data protection law, subject to certain exemptions, in connection with our processing of your personal data, including the right:
to find out if we use your personal data, access your personal data and receive copies of your personal data;
to have inaccurate/incomplete information corrected and updated;
in certain circumstances, to have your details deleted from systems that we use to process your personal data or have the use of your personal data restricted in certain ways;
to object to certain processing of your data by UCC;
to exercise your right to data portability where applicable (i.e. obtain a copy of your personal data in a commonly used electronic form;
where we have relied upon consent as a lawful basis for processing, to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;
to not be subject to solely automated decision;
to request that we stop sending you direct marketing communications.
If you wish to avail of these rights, please write to: The Information Compliance Manager, University College Cork, 4 Carrigside, College Road, Cork (or email foi@ucc.ie).
In order to protect your privacy, you may also be asked to provide suitable proof of identification. If any of your details are incorrect please let us know and we will amend them.
Queries or Complaints
If you have any complaints in connection with our processing of your personal data, you can contact UCC’s Information Compliance Manager: Information Compliance Manager, Office of Corporate & Legal Affairs, University College Cork, Western Road, Cork E: foi@ucc.ie Tel: +353 21 4903949.
You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Commission if you are unhappy with our processing of your personal data. Details of how to lodge a complaint can be found on the Data Protection Commission’s website (www.dataprotection.ie), or by telephoning 1890 252 231.
Revisions to Privacy Statement
The University may revise this privacy statement from time to time. Changes to this privacy statement will be posted here so you should periodically check this page to review the most recent statement. If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of the University’s websites should be referred to the Information Compliance Manager at the address set out above.
Last updated: 25 May 2018
Procedures
Guidelines/Standards
Standards
University College Cork
Coláiste na hOllscoile Corcaigh
College Road, Cork T12 K8AF
+353 (0)21 490 3000
